<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>architecture on Haile Lagi</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/tags/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in architecture on Haile Lagi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:03:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hailelagi.com/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What drives you?</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/what-drives-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 12:13:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/what-drives-you/</guid><description>Why do you wake up in the morning? why do you brush your teeth?
I&amp;rsquo;ve asked myself this question many times. More than once? there was no answer. So I didn&amp;rsquo;t leave my bed. I didn&amp;rsquo;t brush my teeth. Existence seemed to my active imagination a terribly bothersome load.
Here&amp;rsquo;s another entry into my diary. It&amp;rsquo;s been too long since I introspected, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the past. After all this is my selfish corner of the internet.</description></item><item><title>Break your next server</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/dev/break-your-next-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/dev/break-your-next-server/</guid><description>Your friendly neighbourhood aspiring junior dev&amp;rsquo;s guide to understanding the philosophy of fault tolerance in servers. A series of rants and odd thoughts. I want to propose something, break your next server, on purpose. Nope that title isn&amp;rsquo;t clickbait, but I hope you spare me a few moments to explain. Runtime errors are the last thing you want to happen in your code right? Especially if it&amp;rsquo;s running in &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo;, but you know&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>The weight of choice is heavy</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/dev/the-weight-of-choice-is-heavy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 18:46:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/dev/the-weight-of-choice-is-heavy/</guid><description>A humble aspiring junior dev&amp;rsquo;s guide to probabilistic thought. A series of rants and odd thoughts. What are the odds? I&amp;rsquo;ve spent quite a few hours invested in implementing a seemingly innocent feature of a game I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on as part of my learning in the world of functional programming with Elixir. I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you with the details, I haven&amp;rsquo;t even finished making the game, the prelude to discovering this problem is an innocent one.</description></item><item><title>Schrödinger, cats and boxes.</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/dev/schrodinger-cats-and-boxes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 17:20:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/dev/schrodinger-cats-and-boxes/</guid><description>#A humble aspiring junior dev&amp;rsquo;s guide to programmatic thought. A series of rants and odd thoughts.
“And the earth was without form, and void; and darkness was upon the face of the deep. And the Spirit of God moved upon the face of the waters.” Genesis 1:2
If functional programming were a cat? It&amp;rsquo;d be a black cat. Cats are a lot like functional programming, herein referred affectionately to as fp.</description></item><item><title>Conquering costlemark tower(and what it taught me about programming and life)</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/conquering-costlemark-towerand-what-it-taught-me-about-programming-and-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 04:59:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/conquering-costlemark-towerand-what-it-taught-me-about-programming-and-life/</guid><description>In the game Final fantasy XV there&amp;rsquo;s a curious dungeon called costlemark tower. Firstly? It&amp;rsquo;s not a tower&amp;hellip; lol. It&amp;rsquo;s a long 4 hour(*for me) descent into darkness. The horrible thing about dungeons? You can&amp;rsquo;t save your progress. It&amp;rsquo;s a cramped space and it&amp;rsquo;s eternally &amp;ldquo;nighttime&amp;rdquo;. In ffxv nighttime is where the toughest monsters come out to play. The first time I attempted to peek into this dungeon I was grossly underleveled and underprepared.</description></item><item><title>Process</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/process/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/process/</guid><description>Seeing as my blog gets practically no real attention. It is a place where I get to air thoughts as I wish. To the deep deep space, through numerous protocols and packets of &amp;ldquo;words&amp;rdquo; flow. Into bits&amp;hellip; a tiny tiny voice. When I wish, days in a row or months apart. About lovers or technical details. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. What matters is the thought must be put to words sent into the world, into a place that never forgets.</description></item><item><title>Mediocrity.</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/mediocrity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 15:39:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/mediocrity/</guid><description>me•di•o•cre mē″dē-ō′kər► adj.Of ordinary or undistinguished quality. synonym: average. Of moderate degree or quality; middling; indifferent; ordinary. One of middling quality, talents, or merit. Somehow somewhere in the middle of all of this I have achieved mediocrity. Odd isn&amp;rsquo;t it? In all my arrogance, in all my pretensions to being for lack of a richer vocabulary &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo;. I have reached the limits of what my mind can comprehend. I think I consistently overestimate what it is that I can accomplish.</description></item><item><title>Panic?</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/panic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 04:43:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/panic/</guid><description>So what&amp;rsquo;s this all about? I think for a while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been in panic mode. Worrying excessively over the future, over-analyzing and burdening myself with worry. Consider some of my previous articles where I expand on and detail my past experiences and failures. How they&amp;rsquo;ve dramatically shifted my life course from how I thought it would be, to how it actually ended up becoming. Sipping my really really dark cup of coffee this morning as I&amp;rsquo;m about to re-dive into html and css I realize maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve got this all wrong.</description></item><item><title>Deprecation v1</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/deprecation-v1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/deprecation-v1/</guid><description>Deprecation lol. It&amp;rsquo;s a funny word. I only came across it recently when reading the python documentation and some language feature was &amp;lsquo;deprecated&amp;rsquo; loool what does that even mean? Turns out, that&amp;rsquo;s the perfect word to describe what&amp;rsquo;s going on with me right now.
A few weeks ago I wrote about how bleak my future career prospects are as a chemical engineer in Nigeria really are. Some of this of course is due to my own incompetence, negligence and let it be said lack of grit.</description></item><item><title>So far..so good?</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/so-far-so-good/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 23:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/so-far-so-good/</guid><description>I begin this humble blog post with a beautiful art piece by ramin nazer an artist I randomly came across on the internet. &amp;ldquo;The obstacle is the path&amp;rdquo;.
How desperately do I wish these words were true. Today was not a good day, I have spent almost two days working on a &amp;ldquo;coding bat&amp;rdquo; problem I could not solve. I thought that I could do it, I really thought if I tried and tried that I could do it&amp;hellip; yet I couldn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>I Quit.</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/i-quit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 08:16:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/i-quit/</guid><description>This is going to be a dry, unedited, unpolished post. This blog was created to document my thoughts on my journey through learning and self-discovery. Exit now if you have accidentally ventured unprepared for what lies ahead.
For those of you(who am I talking to? My future self? My readers? Both I suppose) that do not know I have for a period of about a year now been &amp;ldquo;hired&amp;rdquo; at a little known transcription website.</description></item><item><title>Pure Will</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/pure-will/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 21:08:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/pure-will/</guid><description>There comes a time in every classical hero&amp;rsquo;s journey that he must come to grips with. A crooked blade of potential and talent waiting to be molded in the fire of hardship, pain and challenge.
First you must set the stage, for there is no hero without a kingdom. No great individual without a society to declare such a person great. This is a hard time to be young in Nigeria.</description></item><item><title>Year.</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/year/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:56:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/year/</guid><description>Year year year year year year year year year year year year year year year year year so after many many year the time had come for the year to end in a very yearly fashion for the years and years party of the awesomeness of the chateau du vale were simply too amazing to pass up this year also in the news this year the yearly year of the harvest year thing of years has come to be a yearly thing annually or yearly?</description></item><item><title>The Problem with Economics</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/the-problem-with-economics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:44:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/the-problem-with-economics/</guid><description>This is a rant on a topic I&amp;rsquo;m fairly acquainted with and have no formal education in except the various books on economic theory I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the years purely out of interest. Forgive my many inaccuracies and off topic devolving into philosophy. If you have a differing opinion, see any error in my reasoning or I have my facts wrong. Kindly direct me further to the path of enlightenment, I&amp;rsquo;m eager to learn and genuinely not above being wrong (if you have a reasonable and sound argument based on facts) .</description></item><item><title>An obsession takes root</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/an-obsession-takes-root/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 17:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/diary/an-obsession-takes-root/</guid><description>Essay into the mind of a learning self taught v2.1 “Anxiety is the dizziness of freedom.” — Søren Kierkegaard
I think to answer complex important questions, it&amp;rsquo;s important to realize there isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a singular path.
There are often parallels between answers and methodologies. Often overlapping in how they guide the process, meaning the overall outcome is simply all that&amp;rsquo;s important given constraints. It&amp;rsquo;s funny, because I&amp;rsquo;ve never internalized this.</description></item><item><title>A villain story</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/travelling/a-villain-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:49:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/travelling/a-villain-story/</guid><description>Hey everyone, Before we delve into this its topic matter, it&amp;rsquo;s well&amp;hellip;controversial? I&amp;rsquo;ve been careful in selecting content for this blog, but I think its time to rock the boat a bit.
​ Nigeria is a country which has deeply religious and cultural ties, the origins of which go not only back to the time the country itself was founded and colonised, but to when more &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; religions were the norm.</description></item><item><title>White Ghosts and Dark Memories</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/travelling/white-ghosts-and-dark-memories/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:17:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/travelling/white-ghosts-and-dark-memories/</guid><description>1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9 and 10. It probably took that voice in your head, the whole of a few seconds to comprehend and interpret that to some degree. Okay let&amp;rsquo;s be honest I&amp;rsquo;m not a neuroscientist or anything, so don&amp;rsquo;t take that on authority, at any level&amp;hellip;(just saying) I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the inner workings of the mind, or even a tiny bit of empirical knowledge about the brain, but we can safely infer the mind takes &amp;ldquo;some&amp;rdquo; time to process information.</description></item><item><title>The Ghost of Christmas Post</title><link>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/travelling/the-ghost-of-christmas-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 08:23:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hailelagi.com/posts/travelling/the-ghost-of-christmas-post/</guid><description>Hey everyone, In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed and have somehow being in a coma and just woke up at the exact time your browser opened up this blog, its CHRISTMAS!!!!!! so merry Christmas. This is a Holiday Special article that&amp;rsquo;s seriously on a not so serious note.
Quite recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself in these brief sedated states where I simply stare and my mind seems to wander, not to anywhere in particular actually, I just feel calm and present, my thoughts seem to vanish and I just feel tranquil.</description></item></channel></rss>